Guide to the Francis Harley Scheetz papers, 1740-1963, 1947-1969 (bulk)
Scheetz, Francis Harley papers, 1740-1963, 1947-1969 (bulk)
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Francis Harley Scheetz papers, 1740-1963, 1947-1969 (bulk)
2-10-1109
Francis Harley Scheetz, 1894-1968.
12.5 cubic ft.
Lecture notes, diplomas, correspondence, and other papers. Also, photographs, prints, maps, a portrait, and vases.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes materials relating to Scheetz' student days and papers from his work as a Cornell trustee and presidential councillor. Also, photographs; prints; four world maps prepared for King Louis XV of France (1740, 1741); a portrait of General Henry Dearborn, a Revolutionary War patriot; two Sèvres vases (gifts to General Dearborn from Louis Philippe); information concerning the Xth International Congress on the History of Science (1962); Theta Delta Chi correspondence; postcards; Scheetz' biographical data; and World War I officer training information.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Francis H. Scheetz, a prominent Philadelphia lawyer, was a member of the Cornell University Board of Trustees from 1951-1967, and then a trustee emeritus and presidential councillor until his death in 1968. He was a recipient of the Cornell Medal for outstanding service to the University. (Cornell University Class of 1916)
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes materials relating to Scheetz' student days, including lecture notes, diplomas, and Cornell Class of 1916 correspondence and reunion and fundraising material; papers from his work as a Cornell trustee and presidential councillor concerning student housing, Cornell United Religious Work, information concerning the Faculty Committee on Academic Freedom and Tenure, the Charles J. Quillman, Jr. Fellowship (1952-1964), Cornell Club of New York, Marquis Foundation, Society for the Humanities, Glee Club, the Cornell Laboratory of Ornithology, the Aeronautical Laboratory, Cornell University Survey of Administrative Management (Volumes 1-5), student affairs, and minutes and other materials of the University Council and Trustees. Also, photographs; prints; four world maps prepared for King Louis XV of France (1740, 1741); a portrait of General Henry Dearborn, a Revolutionary War patriot; two Sèvres vases (gifts to General Dearborn from Louis Philippe); information concerning the Xth International Congress on the History of Science (1962); Theta Delta Chi correspondence; postcards; Scheetz' biographical data; and World War I officer training information.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Scheetz, Francis Harley, 1894-1968.; Dearborn, Henry, 1751-1829.; Charles J. Quillman, Jr. Fellowship.; Cornell Club of New York.; Cornell University. Aeronautical Laboratory.; Cornell University. Board of Trustees.; Cornell University. Class of 1916.; Cornell University. Council.; Cornell University. Faculty Committee on Academic Freedom and Tenure.; Cornell University. Glee Club.; Cornell University. Laboratory of Ornithology.; Cornell University. Society for the Humanities.; Cornell University Survey of Administrative Management.; Cornell United Religious Work.; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University--Religion.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.; Cornell University--Students.; Marquis Foundation.; Theta Delta Chi (Cornell University); International Congress on the History of Sciences (Xth: 1962)
Subjects:
Academic freedom.; Fund raising.; Student housing.; Teachers--Tenure.; Lawyers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Maps.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
All dates given in the container list are approximate.
CONTAINER LIST
- C.U. course and lecture notes--Sibley College (Box 1)
- World War I material, i.e. officer training, gas courses, general orders, maps, photos, etc. (Box 1)
- Greater Cornell Committee, 1947-1951 (Box 2)
- Cornell University Council and Trustees, 1950-1957 (Box 2)
- Law note books (Box 2)
- Cornell University Council and Trustees, 1958-1964 (Box 3)
- Cornell University Class of '16, Fiscal Committee, 1940-1962 (Box 3)
- Cornell University Class of '16, correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, anniversary dinner, 1956 (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, reunion, 1966 (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, fundraising, 1959-1960 (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, fundraising, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, fundraising, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, 50th reunion, 1963 (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, 45th reunion correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, Preiffer Fund, 1963-1965 (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, fundraising prior to 1959, 1951-1953 (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, chair endowment (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, visiting professorships (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, James S. Jamieson Chair (Box 4)
- Cornell University Class of '16, Jane McCurdy Ford, 1961-1965 (Box 4)
- Younger Graduates Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
- Aspirants for Cornell University, 1960-1965 (Box 4)
- Eric S. Erickson, 1945-1958 (Box 4)
- Moakley House, 1948-1950 (Box 4)
- Cornell Fund, 1960-1964 (Box 5)
- Cornell University Investment Pool, 1964-1965 (Box 5)
- Bequests and gifts, 1961-1965 (Box 5)
- Fundraising, gifts and Council meetings, 1960s (Box 5)
- Minutes of University Council, 1952-1956 (Box 6)
- Minutes of University Council, 1956-1958 (Box 6)
- C.U. taxation re: life income agreement, 196?-1964 (Box 6)
- Conflict of interest and business ethics, 1962 (Box 6)
- Physics-ARPA construction project, 1962 (Box 6)
- Xth International Congress of History of Science, 1962 (Box 6)
- Liberalism at university level, 1962-1964 (Box 6)
- Eugene M. Kaufman, Jr. Collection, 1960-1965 (Box 6)
- Griffis Faculty Club, N. Y. City, 1963 (Box 6)
- Centennial, 1962-1964 (Box 6)
- Marquis Foundation, 1952-1955 (Box 6)
- Cornell Club of New York, 1962-1964 (Box 6)
- Presidential selection, 1961-1963 (Box 6)
- Aeronautical Lab., 1962 (Box 6)
- Rumsey bequest, 1960-1963 (Box 6)
- Sarah M. Kaemmerling estate, 1958-1965 (Box 6)
- C.U. group housing, 1962-1964 (Box 7)
- N.Y.S. Dormitory Authority, 1962 (Box 7)
- Group housing, 1951-1965 (Box 7)
- C.U.R.W., 1959-1964 (Box 7)
- C.U.R.W. correspondence, 1953-1961 (Box 7)
- C.U.R.W., 1961-1963 (Box 7)
- Glee Club, 1961-1962 (Box 7)
- Lab. of Ornithology, 1963-1964 (Box 7)
- Charles R. Quillman, Jr. Fellowship, 1946-1966 (Box 7)
- W.H.C.U., 1959 (Box 7)
- Society for the Humanities, 1960-1967 (Box 7)
- Charter, 1959-1960 (Box 7)
- Arts and Science Council, 1960-1964 (Box 7)
- Bequests--life income agreements, 1954-1966 (Box 7)
- Student affairs, 1959-1965 (Box 7)
- Special bequests and endowments, 1954-1963 (Box 7)
- Alumni Association, 1963-1966 (Box 7)
- C.U. Survey of Administrative Management, Vols. 1-5 (Box 8)
- Cornell Tax Conference, 1960-1962 (Box 8)
- Many folders concerning Trustee affairs. Also includes biographical and historical data concerning the Scheetzes (Box 8)
- Graduate Hospital, University of Pennsylvania, 1958-1959 (Box 9)
- Mill Creek Valley Conservation, 1934-1966 (Box 9)
- Printed material (Box 10)
- Printed material (Box 11)
- Museum items
  - Portrait of General Henry Dearborn, Mu. 882
  - Pr. of Sevres porcelain covered urns (vases), Mu. 883-884